Sai Krishna Teja Pothapragada

Software Engineering Professional

linkedin.com/sai-krishna-teja

+1(209) 319 7467

Technologically-sophisticated professional with expertise designing, coding, and developing software applications, while ensuring optimum performance, uptime, and efficiency. Demonstrated success in developing backend / REST API, data models, and standalone services, while automating various processes for customers. Created several front-end UI applications in Angular & React including Micro-frontends. Adept at identifying, interpreting, and analysing user requirements to deliver product in line with user needs. Instrumental in converting technical requirements into understandable language for non-technical users. Strong relationship-building, team leadership, and communication skills evidenced by ability to excel at establishing and nurturing collaborative relationships with employees and management.

Technical Proficiencies

Languages: JAVA, JavaScript, CSS, Angular, React, Python

Frameworks & Technologies: Spring, Spring Boot, Angular (13-16), NextJs (React), TypeScript, Log4j, Tanzu

(Cloud foundry), AWS, Azure, Confluent Kafka, API Gateway, APIGEE, Spring Cloud,

Kubernetes(k8s)

Web Services & Database: REST, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Cassandra, Redis

Tools & IDE: Git, JIRA, Postman, Maven, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Swagger, Jenkins, Urban

code deploy, GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket, ServiceNow

Testing Tools: Junit, Mockito, Cypress (E2E Web & API Testing), Jest (React), Karma (Angular)

Career Experience

Wells Fargo Mar 2021 - Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Understood the requirements from business & identified the bounded contexts and developed various microservices, micro frontends for Digital.
- Co-ordinated and lead the teams into building scalable, efficient & resilient microservices in java and frontend in React using Typescript.
- All the microservices are developed in Java 11 and Migrated to Java 17. Following is the tech stack used for the projects: Spring boot, Spring Cloud, Swagger, Mongo DB, Kafka, Log4J, Circuit Breaker.
- Worked with various cloud offerings available in the Wells Fargo like Tanzu (Cloud Foundry with Kubernetes) and Azure to Host the microservices and front-end.
- Worked with Confluent Kafka to consume and produce various transactional and analytical data which is used for Prediction Analysis.
- Trained teams on cloud (Azure Fundamentals & AWS) for development & also APIGEE for API Management and gateway.
- TDD & BDD implementation for both Back-End (Cucumber & JUNIT) and Front-End (Jest & Cypress)
- Created Dashboards in Splunk and Grafana for Monitoring and Alerting the Microservices.
- Created Reverse Proxy and Enabled API Management for all Microservices.
- Authored & Optimized PLSQL stored procedures and indexed tables in Oracle for better performance.

JPMorgan Chase Oct 2017 – Mar 2021

Senior Software Engineer

• Converted a huge monolith application into several Microservices and Micro-Frontends to make it cloud ready and integrated them with many customers (Chase Digital, Chase Banking)

- Worked with product managers to re-architect a multi-page web app into a single page web-app using react
 in TypeScript and redux and reduced the initial page load time and increased the performance along with
 design.
- Consumed Kafka topics in batches to refresh the Customer Accounts for delinquency.
- Decoupled a huge monolith application with Domain driven design and extracted microservices and made it efficient and manageable.
- Written many PLSQL queries & stored Procedures and optimized them for performance
- Built RESTful APIs that served data to the JavaScript front-end based on dynamically chosen user inputs that handled over 80,000 concurrent users
- Developed monitoring solutions for data path programming in private and public cloud environments.
- Built applications using REST APIs to consume services that mirror traffic from AWS environment using agents deployed on EC2 instances.

Deloitte Jan 2017 – Oct 2017

Senior Analyst

 Served as full stack developer and built an inhouse Performance management system with Analytical Data for Partners.

- Hosted the Restful APIs on Azure cloud.
- Designed frontend architecture and CSS framework standard for the application.
- Built a Security tool to ensure proper administration & risk-free work for both operations and IT team
- Worked on Kubernetes deployment and management for containerized applications. Skilled in configuring and optimizing clusters for performance and scalability. Proficient in troubleshooting and ensuring high availability in Kubernetes environments.

Cognizant Jul 2013 – Jan 2017

Programmer Analyst

- Worked on development of One transport which is one stop cab booking, whether it may be Ad hoc Cab or late-night cab. Employees can book, cancel, or reschedule. Managers can approve or reject requests. Billing is automatically taken from Project account.
- Built an in-house Recruitment management System which facilitates from candidates interview to new hire onboarding activities.
- Worked for Navigator, which is a unified resource for self-service-based query resolution.
- Worked on creating Azure pipelines for various projects for continuous integration and continuous deployment

Education

Birla Institute of Technology & Sciences

2019 - 2020

Masters in Data Analytics

Sreenidhi Institute of Science and Technology (Affiliate to JNTU)

2009 - 2013

Bachelors in Technology (Electrical & Electronic Engineering)